所以对于左边的示例函数
So for the example function on the left, which
你可能还记得我们以前在
you may remember we worked on partitioning in an earlier
在阅读中锻炼，我们想要
exercise in this reading, we want
在分区中记录测试策略
to document the testing strategy in the partitioning
我们用的。
that we use.
我们有一个办法--
And here's one way that we can do that--
在我们的测试文件中写一条评论
by writing a comment in our testing file
这说明了我们如何划分输入。
that says how we partition the inputs.
而且，对于每个测试用例
And that also, for each test case
我们通过这个分区产生的，
that we generate as a result of that partition,
指示它实际覆盖的部分。
indicates which parts it actually covers.
这个策略实际上解决了一些边界值
This strategy actually addresses some boundary values that we
以前都没考虑过。
didn't even consider before.
所以这样做很重要，尤其是
So it'll be important to do that, particularly
当你写测试的时候
when you're writing up your tests
对于本课程中的习题集。
for the problem sets in this course.
现在判断测试套件的一种方法
Now one way to judge a test suite
就是问这个程序的执行情况如何。
is to ask how thoroughly it exercises the program.
这个想法叫做覆盖。
This idea is called coverage.
有三种常见的保险，
And there are three common kinds of coverage,
有点精疲力尽了。
sort of an increasing level of exhaustiveness.
首先是对账单的覆盖。
First is statement coverage.
问的是每个语句至少有一个
And that's asking is every statement run by at least one
测试用例，程序中的每个语句。
test case, every statement in the program.
第二个是分支覆盖，它更强大
Second is branch coverage, which is stronger
比报表覆盖率高。
than statement coverage.
它说如果或当每一个陈述
It says that for every if or while statement
在程序中——这些程序中有分支
in the program-- so these have branches in them-- that
条件测试是从if开始的吗--
is the condition test beginning with the if--
或者while的每个迭代——都是布尔测试。
or every iteration of the while-- is a Boolean test.
问题是真与假
And the question is are both the true and false
某个测试用例所进行的布尔测试的方向？
direction of that Boolean test taken by some test case?
它向两个方向分支，
Does it branch in both directions,
是真是假？
both true and false?
然后最强的是路径覆盖。
And then the strongest one is path coverage.
所有可能的分支组合--
So is every possible combination of branches--
这是整个程序的所有路径——通过一些测试来探索
that is every path through the program-- explored by some test
案子？
case?
所以分支覆盖比语句覆盖强，
So branch coverage is stronger than statement coverage,
也就是说，它通常需要更多的测试来实现。
that is, it typically requires more tests to achieve it.
路径覆盖比分支覆盖强。
And path coverage is stronger than branch coverage.
在业界，100%的声明覆盖率是一个共同的目标。
In industry, 100% statement coverage is a common goal.
但即使这样也很难做到，因为你经常
But even that can be hard to get to because you often
有基本上无法达到的防御代码，比如断言
have basically unreachable defensive code, like assertions
那说明你不应该来这里。
that say you should never get here.
这不是什么不寻常的事。
It's not an unusual thing.
而且这些永远不会被您的测试代码真正调用。
And those would never actually be invoked by your test code.
所以100%的声明覆盖率可能很难。
So 100% statement coverage can be hard.
100%的分支覆盖率是非常理想的。
100% branch coverage is highly desirable.
和安全关键行业规范
And safety critical industry code
有一个比100%的分支更严格的标准
has an even more arduous criteria than 100% branch
覆盖范围，如MCDC，这是一个修改后的决定
coverage, such as MCDC, which is a modified decision
以及条件保险。
and condition coverage.
但不幸的是，100%的路径覆盖，最强的一个，
But unfortunately 100% path coverage, the strongest one,
完全不可能，因为
is completely unfeasible because it
需要一个指数级的测试用例，测试套件
would require an exponentially sized test case, test suite
去实现它。
to achieve it.
现在是获得良好覆盖率的标准方法
Now a standard approach to getting good coverage
在测试套件实现之前添加测试
is to add tests until the test suite achieves
令人满意的报表覆盖率。
satisfactory statement coverage.
换言之，使每一个合理可及的陈述
In other words, so that every reasonably reachable statement
在程序中至少由一个测试用例执行。
in the program is executed by at least one test case.
实际上，您通常衡量语句覆盖率
In practice, you usually measure statement coverage
使用代码覆盖工具
with a code coverage tool which counts
测试运行每个语句的次数
the number of times each statement is run by your test
一套。
suite.
所以有了这样的工具，白盒测试
So with a tool like that, white box testing
其实很简单。
is actually pretty easy.
你先测量黑匣子测试的覆盖率，
You measure the coverage of your black box test first,
然后添加更多的测试用例，直到
and then you add more test cases until you've
设法涵盖了所有重要的陈述。
managed to cover all of the important statements.
有一个很好的Eclipse代码覆盖工具，
There's a good code coverage tool for Eclipse,
名为Eclema，显示在右侧。
called EclEmma, shown on the right.
我鼓励你安装和使用它。
I encourage you to install it and use it.
注意这些线——EclEmma
Notice that the lines-- EclEmma has
为测试套件执行的行上色
colored the lines that have been executed by the test suite
绿色。
green.
未被覆盖的线条是红色的。
The lines that have not been covered are colored red.
如果你从你的覆盖工具中看到这种结果，
If you saw this kind of result from your coverage tool,
你的下一步就是上来
your next step would be to come up
一个导致while循环主体的测试用例
with a test case that causes the body of this while loop
执行并将其添加到测试套件中
to execute and add it to your test suite
使红线变成绿色。
so that the red lines become green.